Denis Yarats

www.denis-yarats.info \diamond denisyarats at gmail dot com

RESEARCH

My research interest is to develop intelligent agents that can communicate with people and perform useful tasks, with the ultimate ambition to liberate people from the burden of mundane routines. I want to advance the areas of NLP and RL through my research, as they allow the emergence of agents that can evolve over time through their interaction, which is an essential trait of intelligence.

EXPERIENCE

Facebook AI Research

June 2016 - Present

Research Engineer

Menlo Park, CA

I focus my research on advancing methods of NLP and RL in the settings of goal-oriented dialogues. Prior to this, I worked on developing state of the art algorithms for Machine Translation.

Quora

September 2013 - June 2016

Staff ML Engineer

Mountain View, CA

I served as a tech lead on the ML team and supported multiple large scale projects, such as engineering a distributed training framework and a real time ranking system. I also developed ranking and content understanding algorithms and enhanced data and release infrastructure. I provided a scalable and performant implementation for various ML algorithms, some of my work was open sourced (http://github.com/quora/qmf).

Bing, Microsoft

November 2011 - September 2013

Software Engineer

Bellevue. WA

I worked on improving the relevance of the search engine. In particular, I enhanced the performance and accuracy of the entity conflation algorithm by means of clusterization and classification. In addition, I reduced the latency of the ingestion data pipeline by optimizing the underlying algorithms and developing distributed analogues.

Yandex

June 2011 - November 2013

Software Engineer

Moscow, Russia

I focused on building an algorithm to generate predictions for car traffic jams in Moscow, with the goal to improve the city's severe road congestion. I developed an ML solution that leveraged both offline data and real-time signals in order to reliably forecast roadblocks.

PUBLICATIONS

Hierarchical Text Generation and Planning for Strategic Dialogue D.Yarats*, M. Lewis*. Preprint.

December 2017

Deal or No Deal? End-to-End Learning for Negotiation Dialogues

June 2017

M. Lewis, D. Yarats, Y. Dauphin, D. Parikh, D. Batra. EMNLP 2017.

Convolutional Sequence to Sequence Learning

April 2017

J. Gehring, M. Auli, D. Grangier, D. Yarats, Y. Dauphin. ICML 2017.

TALKS

Convolutional Sequence to Sequence Learning

November 2017

Treehouse Talk at CLMS, University of Washington.

Convolutional Sequence to Sequence Learning

September 2017

International Conference on Artificial Intelligence (www.aiukraine.com).

PRESS COVERAGE

Deal or no deal? Training AI bots to negotiate

June 2017

http://code.facebook.com/posts/deal-or-no-deal-training-ai-bots-to-negotiate.

A novel approach to neural machine translation

May 2017

http://code.facebook.com/posts/a-novel-approach-to-neural-machine-translation.

TEACHING

Introduction to Deep Learning

September 2016 - Present

Teaching assistant, Facebook.

Discrete Mathematics and Algorithms

September 2011 - November 2011

Lecturer, Yandex School of Data Analysis.

EDUCATION

Belarusian State University

June 2011

M.S. in Computer Science & Math.

Belarusian State University

June 2010

B.S. in Computer Science & Math.

SKILLS

PyTorch/Torch, Python, C/C++, CUDA, LATEX.

ACHIEVEMENTS

ACM ICPC World Final

May 2011

Orlando, USA.

Google Code Jam European Final

October 2008

Zurich, Switzerland.

REFERENCES

Michael Lewis

Research Scientist, Facebook AI Research

 $email: \ mikelew is @fb.com$

Dhruv Batra

Assistant Professor, Georgia Institute of Technology email: dbatra@gatech.edu

Larry Zitnick

Research Manager, Facebook AI Research

email: zitnick@fb.com